<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on SihaoPedia ʕ•ᴥ•ʔ</title>
    <link>https://sihaog.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on SihaoPedia ʕ•ᴥ•ʔ</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2023, Sihao Gao.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2023 23:26:48 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sihaog.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What is Epidemiology?</title>
      <link>https://sihaog.github.io/what-is-epidemiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2023 23:26:48 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sihaog.github.io/what-is-epidemiology/</guid>
      <description>Epidemiology has been defined as “the study of the distribution and determinants of disease frequency”.
As definition implies, the study of epidemiology contains two major components:
Description of data Causal analysis Descriptive epidemiology The first part of Epidemiology is to study the distribution of disease, or more simply put, is to describe disease data.
Distribution = describing the pattern of an illness in terms of person, place, and time.
Person: Who has disease (Demographic characteristics: age, sex, ethnicity, etc) Place: Is this disease equally spatially distributed?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multiply your time</title>
      <link>https://sihaog.github.io/multiply-your-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 22:45:54 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sihaog.github.io/multiply-your-time/</guid>
      <description>I just watched an interesting TED Talk on &amp;ldquo;How to Multiply Your Time&amp;rdquo; because I&amp;rsquo;ve been struggling with time management and procrastination these days.
Important ideas came from this video:
Significance Calculation Multiply your time means do significance calculation. Time management is not a logical thing to do, but an emotional thing to deal with.
You MULTIPLY your time by giving yourself the EMOTIONAL PERMISSION to spend time on things TODAY that will give you more time TOMORROW.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JSON Introduction</title>
      <link>https://sihaog.github.io/json-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 14:53:59 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sihaog.github.io/json-introduction/</guid>
      <description>JSON stands for JavaScript Object Notation
a file format for data storage and data exchange JSON stores two types of data An object An Array of values Object An object starts with left curly brace { and ends with a right curly brace }.
Inside of an object, the dictionary is formed by pairs of property names and values.
Each property is separated from each other by a comma ,.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interesting Green Exit Sign</title>
      <link>https://sihaog.github.io/interesting-green-exit-sign/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 16:27:25 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sihaog.github.io/interesting-green-exit-sign/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve just noticed that the exit logo in Beijing Subway and Hong Kong Metro are the same.
Exit sign in Hong Kong MTR: Exit sign in Beijing Subway: High Resolution MTR Sung </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://sihaog.github.io/introduction-to-machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 22:48:11 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sihaog.github.io/introduction-to-machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>Since the emergence of AlphaGo, AlphaFold2, and ChatGPT etc., artificial intelligence technologies (including machine learning) have revolutionalized today&amp;rsquo;s paradigm of scientific research. However, little is known about the principles of the tech itself by people outside of CS areas. This blog is to briefly introduce these concepts.
Before diving into the fancy/mysterious words, we must first understand what learning is in human beings.
What is learning in humans? Gain of knowledge from experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to use GitHub</title>
      <link>https://sihaog.github.io/how-to-use-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2023 15:22:01 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sihaog.github.io/how-to-use-github/</guid>
      <description>What is GitHub? One word: a code hosting platform allowing version control and collaboration.
GitHub vs Git Git is local. Github is remote.
Basics git init creates a new Git repository.
git add adds a local change to the staging area, which is not synced until git commit
git commit captures a snapshot of the staged changes – just like take a photo of the staged repository.
git push uploads the commited respository to the remote repository.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
